[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Okay, well we've talked quite exhaustively about this notion of clustering for
好的 我们已经相当详尽地讨论了聚类这个概念以及
the sake of doing document retrieval, but there are lots,
它在文件检索中的应用 然而还有许多
and lots of other examples where clustering is useful, and
其他的聚类的应用实例
I wanna take some time just to describe a few of them.
我想要花点时间来讲讲其中的一些
So one application is for image search.
其中一个应用是图像搜索
So imagine you're going and you're searching,
那么想象一下你上来要搜索
you go on Google Image search and you type in the word ocean.
你上了谷歌图片搜索 输入关键词海洋
Well it would be really helpful if we could structure all the images we have by
那么很有用的一点是能够把所有的图片组织分类成
some set of categories like ocean, pink flower, dog, sunset, clouds.
诸如海洋 粉色花朵 狗 日落 云彩 等等的类别
So clustering is very helpful for doing structured search.
因此聚类算法对结构检索颇有益处
Another very different application is maybe we wanna group patients by
另一个非常不同的应用是我们可能会想要将病人
their medical condition.
根据病况进行分组
So here a goal might be to better
所以这里的目标可能是更好地
characterize subpopulations as well as different diseases.
特征化疾病亚种和不同的疾病
So as an example, we can look at a whole bunch of patients that have seizures.
举例来说 我们可以锁定一组癫痫患者
So these three brains represent three different patients, and
这里的三个大脑代表三个不同的病人 而
they have different recording setups that are measuring their seizure activity.
他们有各自的癫痫发病活动的记录
And so for each of these patients we get a collection of recordings
对这里的每个病人我们都有一系列
of different seizures that they exhibit over time.
按时间追踪的不同癫痫发作的记录
So each one of these colored squares represents
这里的每个有色方块都代表
a different recording of a seizure.
一条不同的记录
And between these different patients there might be
在这些不同的病人身上可能会
similar types of seizures that appear in these different patients.
发生相似类型的癫痫发作
And so what we can do is we can take all of these seizure recordings from these
我们可以拿这三个病人的所有病情记录
three different patients and think about clustering them.
来考虑如何聚类
And if we identify different types of seizures in this way,
如果我们用这种方法识别出了癫痫的不同类型
this can allow us to better treat the types of patient that
那这就能让我们更好地对症下药
we're observing based on understanding what types seizures they exhibit.
根据他们表现出的癫痫类型来进行治疗
Well another application is thinking about doing product recommendation on Amazon.
那另一个应用是在亚马逊上进行产品推荐
So, for example, on Amazon there are a lot of third parties that come and
比如说 在亚马逊上会有一些第三方卖家
they post some product to be sold.
他们会发布代售的产品
And they provide a label of what that product is.
并且用标签来标示产品属性
So, for example, maybe a person wants to sell a crib and
比如说 有一个人打算卖一个婴儿车
they label the crib, fairly reasonably, as being a furniture item.
他们把这个婴儿床相当合理地标记为家具
So maybe we get posted under the furniture category.
那么我们可能会把它发布到家具类下面
But, if instead, we look at who purchases this item?
那如果我们改从这项物品的购买者的角度来考虑呢？
And we look at their purchase history, and
我们来看看他们的购买记录和
we look at other people with similar purchase histories, so
其他有相似购买记录的消费者
maybe the person who purchased this item also purchased baby car seat, well
那么这些购买者很可能还买了婴儿汽车座椅
then maybe what we can do is maybe we can infer that a better label for this crib,
然后我们可能以此出发 可以为这个婴儿床加上一个更好的标签
which had been labeled furniture is really to have labeled it as a baby product.
原来的家具标签其实应该被改成婴儿用品
So in addition to discovering groups of products that are related, that have.
因此我们不仅可以发现相关联的产品
Based on purchase histories of these items we can also
基于这些物品的购买记录我们也可以
use that to discover groups of related users on Amazon.
来发现亚马逊上相关的用户族群
And that can be used for targeting products to those users.
这些信息可以被用来设计对这些用户的定向产品推荐
And finally we can think about structuring web search results.
最后我们可以考虑组织网页搜索的结果
So, for example,
比方说
search terms can have multiple meanings like the word "cardinal".
搜索词可能有多重意思 比如单词 "cardinal"
If I type this in to Google, maybe I mean I want an article about a cardinal,
如果我在谷歌中输入这个词 我可能想找一篇关于北美红雀的文章
the bird, maybe about the baseball team, or about a cardinal, a religious figure.
可能是想搜索圣路易红雀棒球队 又或者可能是关于宗教人士红衣主教的新闻
So if we can structure out articles based on their content,
因此如果我们可能根据内容来组织这些文章
using the same types of ideas we've talked about in this module,
用我们在这个模块里讲到的思路
then I can improve my search results that I provide to people.
我就可以优化我提供给用户的搜索结果
And the list of applications goes on and on.
类似的应用实例还有很多很多
Another one that's quite interesting is thinking about
另一个很有意思的问题是
collections of neighborhoods and
想一想社区的集合
there are a few applications where you want to discover similar neighborhoods.
以及一些需要查找相似社区的实际问题
One is if we wanna estimate the price of a house at a very small local
其中一个是如果我们想要估计一个房子的价格 并且是对
regional level.
一个相当小的地区中的房子做估计
So in this case, it challenges the fact that we only have a few, or
在这种情况下 很有挑战性的一点是我们只有非常少 或者
very often, no house sale observations within a very small neighborhood.
在很多时候 没有任何在这个小的地区中的房屋出售的信息
So if we wanna estimate the value of the house in that neighborhood
那如果我们想要对这个社区中的房子进行估价
at a point in time, it's very hard to do that
当前来看是非常困难的
because we have no other houses to base our estimate off of in that neighborhood.
因为我们在这个社区中找不到参照点
However, if we can discover other neighborhoods that have
但是 如果我们发现其他社区有
similar types of house dynamics, house price dynamics, then
相似的房产情况和相似的房价波动趋势 那么
we can come up with a good estimate of the house in the neighborhood with few or
我们还是可以较好地估计出这个社区的房价 即使
no sales by leveraging information from this other neighborhood
这个社区中没有或者少有房屋交易记录 我们仍可靠利用这些其他的社区中
that was discovered to be related to the current neighborhood.
的信息来推断
So, the idea is to discover clusters of neighborhoods, and
因此 用这个对社区进行聚类的想法
then within those clusters we can share information like these house sales
在相同集群中我们可以实现对房屋交易这样的信息的共享
informations to form better estimates.
并且得到更好的评估结果
So, this is the solution that I'm describing here, is to cluster regions
所以我这里描述的解决方案 就是对
with similar trends, and then share information within a cluster.
又相同趋势的区域进行聚类 并且对集群内实现信息共享
And the same idea of discovering related regions can be used for helping
这个识别相关区域的点子还可以用来帮助
to forecast violent crimes, to better task police forces to different regions.
预测犯罪率 以此来优化各个区域的警力配备
So again once we discover different neighborhoods that have very
那么一旦我们发现不同的社区有非常
similar crime dynamics, we can form better predictions of the rates
相像的犯罪活动的动态 我们就能更好预测
of violent crimes in those neighborhoods and
那些社区的犯罪率并
then use that information to task police to those regions.
用来优化那些区域的警力
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community